

Summary _

Software Engineer specializing in fullstack web development. Interested in problem solving through code. I enjoy doing a variety of hobbies and reading various subjects.

Skills_

Proficient JavaScript/TypeScript, Go, HTML & CSS, SASS, Express, React, Redux, NodeJS, MongoDB, Webpack, Grunt, Gulp, Git

Knowledgeable AWS, SQL, Docker, Electron, Rust, Actix-Web, Elixir, Phoenix, Ecto, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB

Basic C, C++, Java, Lisp, Haskell, ŁTEX, Web Assembly, D3

Work Experience _____

Bloomberg LP New York City

Senior Software Engineer Apr. 2020 - PRESENT

• Worked as a fullstack engineer on various internal tools for Bloomberg's security department

Lifion by ADP New York City

FULLSTACK PLATFORM ENGINEER Feb. 2019 - Apr. 2020

- Designed and built i18n pipeline for flagship end-user facing apps
- Built a service to streamline ETL pipeline transformation

ITN Networks New York City

FRONT END ENGINEER Jul. 2019 - Mar. 2019

- Worked on various features on the company's front end codebase with over 1.5 million lines of code with 10 other engineers using React
- · Integrated Cypress testing automation and developed a more reliable end to end testing infrastructure
- Aggressively refactored the codebase to improve performance, readability and maintainability

IrisVR Inc. New York City

FULLSTACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER CONSULTANT

Oct. 2016 - Mar. 2018

- Implemented build system on company's front end and desktop app development environment using Webpack
- Developed the company's front end client using React and Redux
- Developed the company's desktop client using Electron and React
- · Designed failure-point handling to handle disconnections between several NodeJS backend services gracefully
- Migrated company's MongoDB and AWS Redshift database changes with ensured consistency

Ninthbeat Inc. New York City

CO-FOUNDER & FULLSTACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Mar. 2015 - Dec. 2015

- Built a marketplace platform for musicians to buy and sell their used musical instruments
- Utilized MEAN stack to develop a full-stack solution for the platform

Education

Queens College Flushing, NY

M.A. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (3.9 GPA) 2016 - 2018

Alliance Theological Seminary

Manhattan, NY

M.Div. in Theological Studies 2010 - 2013

Bina Nusantara University

Jakarta, Indonesia

B.Eng. in Industrial Engineering 2004 - 2008

SEPTEMBER 1, 2020 CHRISTIAN SAKAI · RÉSUMÉ